# Richard Eldridge

# **SUMMARY:**

Self-driven, coding boot camp graduate experienced in programming websites from scratch and well-versed in multiple coding languages. Specializations include Python, JavaScript, and CSS3. Professional skills include excellent verbal and written communications, a meticulous eye for detail, working in a team environment, and accomplishing tasks through a goal-oriented mindset. Previous professional skills in troubleshooting complex problems developed from 5 years of maintenance, diagnosis and repair of motor and power equipment.

### SKILLS:

Proficient: Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code (VSCode), Bootstrap

**Knowledgeable:** Flask, Django, Heroku, MongoDB **Familiar:** PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Service (AWS), Stripe

#### **PROJECTS:**

Recipe Compendium: Fat Raccoon

Single Developer, Jun. 2021

# **Link** Repository

An application that serves as a community created recipe compendium that allows users to store and view recipes with a colorful and intuitive UX.

- NoSQL database, MongoDB used to allow for maximum document flexibility and search speed.
- CSS3 / SVG art used to replace need for images and help lower load time for users.
- The Flask framework was implemented because of its minimal footprint and was used as a tool to build an app which provided a completely unique user experience.

Created with: Python, Flask, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, GitHub, Git, Heroku

E-commerce Website: Eldridge Music Book Emporium

Single Developer, Nov. 2021

# **Link** | Repository

Eldridge Music Book Emporium is a fundamental e-commerce application designed for users to search, rate, and purchase music books. This application utilizes toast notifications for simple interactions and email notifications when users create an account or purchase books.

- Django and Allauth were utilized to meet an accelerated deadline and create fully functional backend and authentication system.
- SQLite3 (development) and PostGreSQL (deployment) database systems were used through Django's model system to allow for quick and easily form validation.
- Stripe's API provided an easy and efficient method to accept and process user payments.

**Created with**: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Service (AWS), JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Visual Studio Code (VSCode), GitHub, Heroku, Stripe

# Wheelchair Accessibility Calculator App: Spinning Wheelchairs

Developer in Team of 4, Sept. 2021

# **Link** | Repository

This JavaScript-powered hackathon project achieved 3rd place in the Trust in SODA 2020 event in conjunction with Code Institute. This rudimentary project was designed to help determine if a hallway or doorway has the adequate space to accommodate a wheelchair's wide turn radius.

- Accessibility was the theme for this hackathon, so this project was streamlined to focus on best accessibility practices over a fancy design.
- To keep the project straightforward, JavaScript and JSON were used to pass information between pages instead of implementing a fully featured backend.
- Agile software development practices were utilized through constant communication via GitPod Projects and Slack which helped determine app features that were feasible.

Created with: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, Git, Visual Studio Code (VSCode), Bootstrap, AGILE

#### **EDUCATION:**

## **Code Institute, Dublin**

May 2020 - Nov. 2021

• Certificate in Software Development

# **Sprayberry High School**

May 2003

High School Diploma

### **EXPERIENCE:**

# SGPS ShowRig, Inc., Norcross, GA

Feb. 2015 – Jun. 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020

- Troubleshooted and serviced broken motors, controllers, and power equipment.
- Oversaw maintenance, cleaning, and organization of the motor department.
- Reported damaged and missing equipment and ordered parts for repairs.

### Power and Control Technician

Feb. 2018 - Nov. 2019

- Serviced broken power and control equipment.
- Ensure inventory is accurate and well maintained.

## Department Head of Rigging

Feb. 2015 - Feb. 2018

- Streamline department's physical layout to increase productivity and make work more accessible to those outside of the department.
- Setup methods to check, clean, and maintain equipment.